Inventory of the Garrett Family Papers 1786-1928
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Letters, 1825-1928, n.d. (Box 1-2)
  - Letters, 1910-1928., 36 items. (Box-folder 2:1)
    - C[omfort] L.G. Nottingham, Baltimore, [Maryland], to "auntie" [?], n.p., 24 August n.y., 8 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Has found jet-headed pins inexpensive and so has purchased some as they are very useful in mourning; mentions that Cousin Kate and Cousin Richard have gone to Frederick; is proud of the way she is running the house in their absence; has found that grey, solid black, and drab are the most popular colors for clothing for a lady; informs her that calico suits are very fashionable; suggests that the girls send some money to her a few weeks before they need their winter clothing so that she has time to look around and find the most reasonable prices; mentions that Miss White and Mr. Lynch were married and off to Sand Shoal before anyone at Eastville knew the wedding had occurred; was sad to learn that Mr. Craighill and Maggie lost their young child to sickness on a visit to Northampton; believes she has found a situation for her father; has been able to find the English needles at only one place; mentions that Sallie Upshur will be teaching at Staunton next year.
    - Mary W. Garrett, Gloucester, [Virginia], to "father" [?], n.p., n.d., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Asks that he send for her on Wednesday if possible, but will be ready to go on the day they originally agreed to if he desires it; thanks him for sending her on this visit; believes that Loyd [sic] may come for a visit to Williamsburg; asks him to tell Van that when she returns she wants to read Shakespear [sic] to appear "wise and knowing."
    - Mary [?], Baltimore, [Maryland], to "Father" [?], n.p., 24 June n.y., 8 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Has been hoping that she would receive a letter from him; believes the change in air has done her well; was able to see Cousin Kate, but Cousin Richard has gone up to Philadelphia and Bayly had yet to hear of her arrival; thanks her father for this trip and promises to "look out for a rich beau, and when I get very rich I will pay you back"; asks why none of their family's names have become famous and insists that merit has been overlooked in favor of locality; asks that he write to Cousin Monroe as they have few rich relations and "cannot afford to slight any of these"; informs him that Mary's baby is doing well but only wishes that Mary would leave the nurse behind.
    - J.W. Mercer, n.p., to Mrs. Dr. [Robert] Garrett, n.p., 24 Oct[ober] n.y., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Thanks her for her gift; informs her that the services he performs for her are done with "the utmost pleasure"; hopes that God keeps her well.
    - J.M. King [?], n.p., to Ro[bert] Garrett, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. Illegible handwriting. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Concerns claims.
    - Mary [W. Garrett], n.p. to "Aunt" [?], n.p., n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Thanks her for the presents she sent; informs her that Lottie is invited to Miss Lena Harding's wedding; has heard that Brother [?] can "play a number of duets, had stopped chewing, wore kid gloves to school, and never got mad"; shares more news of friends and family.
    - Two letters written on the same page, 9 April n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Mary [W. Garrett], Williamsburg, [Virginia], to "Aunt" [?], n.p., 9 April n.y. Informs her that Father determined there is no position for a young lawyer in Williamsburg, so Winder has gone to Texas to find employment; is saddened to have Winder gone; wishes that Cousin Comfort accompany her [Aunt] on her visit; will send the hats by way of Florence Custis because she would rather they be trimmed there; mentions that Miss Henry was engaged to her cousin, but just before the wedding "she had conscientious scruples, and discarded him and all of the family." 4 pp. ALS.
      Also contains the letter of: Lottie [Garrett], n.p., to "Auntie" [?], n.p. Asks if she could only stay in Baltimore two or three more days so that Florence can deliver the bonnets; trusts Comfort's taste more than anyone and would like her to trim the bonnets. 1 p. ALS.
    - Mary [W. Garrett], Williamsburg, Virginia, to Miss Susie Garrett, n.p., Dec[ember] n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Chastises her for not writing since she left; was asked by Charlie McLean to send his love; informs her that Charlie was saddened to not see her [SG] before she left as he does not think he'll be able to make it back to Williamsburg for another three years; asks that she have her photograph taken as she [MWG] would really like one; shares news from Van's letter.
    - Mary Johnston, [Williamsburg, Virginia], to Miss [Lottie] Garrett, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Believes the drive should be postponed until Wednesday as the weather is bad; "Williamsburg evidently has its April in March."
    - W.H. Martin, Convalescent Camp, [?], to Mr. [?] Garrett, n.p., 1 Oct[ober] n.y., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Thanks him for his and his daughter's kindness; would like to thank him also on behalf of the convalescents for his kindness.
    - [?], n.p., to Carra [?], n.p., n.d., 4 pages. AL. Incomplete. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Thanks her for the gift she has sent by Hattie; informs her that she gave her a priceless gift.
    - Mary Johnston, n.p., to Miss [Lottie] Garrett, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Informs her that she and Coralie will be there around six o'clock; regrets that Miss Garrett's sister will not be there.
    - Talbot Sweeney, American Hotel, to "Ellick," A[lexander] C. Garrett, Williamsburg, Virginia, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Has spoken to the Governor and learned that the position was first offered to Mr. Wise, and when he refused it was offered to Stovall; believes that if Stovall refuses the position, that he [ACG] has a good chance of securing it; feels that had he [ACG] stayed in Richmond after Mr. Wise's refusal, he would have had an excellent chance.
    - [?], n.p., to "Rob" [Dr. Robert M. Garrett?], n.p., n.d., 2 pages. AL. Written over another letter. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Relates the circumstances of his mother's severe illness which caused her excruciating pain.
    - Lotty [Garrett], n.p., to "my dear sisters" [?], n.p., n.d., 1 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Shares news of her doings and of her family.
    - Ada May [?], n.p., to [?], n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Shares a poem with her correspondent.
    - [Comfort L.G. Nottingham], n.p., to [?], n.p., n.d. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Informs her correspondent that the trim she uses for cotton chemises and nightgowns is fairly inexpensive, about ten cents a yard; was able to get wide chintz for twelve and a half cents a yard; fears that it is now all sold.
    - [Comfort L.G. Nottingham], n.p., to [?], n.p., n.d., 1 page. frag. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Feels that her correspondent need not fear small pox; relates how she was living next door to a home in which six people died of the small pox and that the window of her home was not more than three yards from the open window of the house of the sick and she was never taken ill.
    - [?], n.p., to [?], n.p., n.d., 2 pages. frag. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Informs her correspondent that she has "captured 'the catch of Morehead'," a gentleman named James Richard Young; explains that Young is one of the prominent men in North Carolina; will be residing in Raleigh; shares information about his five children, ranging in age from about 22 to ten years old.
  Series 2: Accounts
- Accounts chiefly of Mr. Richard R. Garrett, 1832-1868. (Box-folder 2:2)
  Series 3: Legal Documents
- Legal Documents, 1786-1848. (Box-folder 2:3-7)
  - Will of Edward Moss of York County, 21 February 1786. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Deed in which 1,000 acres of land in Harrison County, Virginia, were sold to John Reedle by John Philips of Virginia, 3 September 1788. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Notice from Robert G. Scott, Captain of the Rifle Company attached to the 68th Regiment, Virginia Militia, to Lieutenant Richard Garrett, 16 March 1818. (Box-folder 2:5)
    Informing him that the officers of the Regiment will meet to begin their training on the fifth Wednesday of April at the Rawleigh Tavern in Williamsburg.
  - Document written by Alexander W. Green swearing that he is acquainted with Timothy Jones, a "free man of colour, and now a resident of York County," who served in the Revolutionary War and lost one of his legs in action at Yorktown, 22 October 1832. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Summons for Callshell Presson [?] to appear in court on behalf of Henry and Levon Smith, accused of assaulting George Elliott, 3 November 1834. (Box-folder 2:5)
    Signed by Samuel Sheild, Clerk of the Court of York County.
  - Documents mainly pertaining to inheritance suits in which Richard Garrett or Alexander C. Garrett served as Commissioner, 1841-1853. (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Documents pertaining to the estate of Polly Pigg, deceased, 1844-1848. (Box-folder 2:7)
  Series 4: Writtings
- Writtings, n.d. (Box-folder 2:8)
  Includes stories, reminiscences, and speeches of various members of the Garrett family.
  Series 5: Calling and Place Cards
- Calling and Place Cards, n.d. (Box-folder 2:9)
  Includes many calling cards and place cards of various members of the Garrett family.
  Series 6: Printed Matter
- Printed Matter, 1851-1900, n.d., 6 items. (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Printed volume of an address at Yorktown delivered by Colonel Alexander C. Garrett, on the anniversary of the Battle of Yorktown, 19 October 1851. (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Pamphlet entitled Facts about Williamsburg and Vicinity, belonging to Miss [Lottie?] Garrett, published in 1900. (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Printed copy of the epitaph of Captain John Smith, n.d. (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Fragment of a newspaper article celebrating Robert E. Lee as a great general, n.d. (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Pamphlet entitled Angel Voices, containing Biblical verses and hymn verses, n.d. (Box-folder 2:10)
    Given to Susan Yardley and Montie from Aunt Mary and Aunt Sue.
  - Printed version of a hymn, given to "his Virginia cousins" by Richard Watson Gilder, composer of the hymn, n.d. (Box-folder 2:10)